很久很久以前，在一个遥远的银河中…
星球大战
第四部 新希望
在这个时候，内战连连
反抗军的飞船从秘密基地袭击邪恶的帝国军
并赢取了初次胜利
在这次战争中
反抗军的间谍窃取了帝国的终极武器“死星”的设计图
死星是一座武装太空站
其威力足以摧毁一个星球
在邪恶的帝国军追捕下
莉娅公主急于将偷得设计图护送回航
用它来解救她的人民，并且使整个银河系获得新生…
你听到了吗？
Did you hear that?
他们毁坏了主反应堆
They shut down the main reactor.
我们肯定完蛋了
We'll be destroyed for sure.
太疯狂了
This is madness.
我们死定了
We're doomed.
公主这次无法脱身了
There'll be no escape for the princess this time.
那是什么？
What's that?
R2-D2，你在哪里？
R2-D2, where are you?
总算找到你了
At last!
你到哪里去了？
Where have you been?
他们就要从这里过来了
They're heading in this direction.
我们该怎么办？
What are we going to do?
我们会被送到开索的乱坟场…
We'll be sent to the spice mines of Kessel...
被捣成碎片的！
smashed into who knows what!
等等，你要去哪里？
Wait a minute. Where are you going?
死星的设计图不在主计算机中
The Death Star plans are not in the main computer.
你截取的那些信息到哪里去了？
Where are those transmissions you intercepted?
你把那些设计图怎么了？
What have you done with those plans?
我们没有截取任何的信息
We intercepted no transmissions.
这是一艘领事飞船
This is a consular ship.
我们在执行外交任务
We're on a diplomatic mission.
如果这是领事飞船…
If this is a consular ship...
那么大使在哪里？
where is the ambassador?
指挥官，掘地三尺也要把那些设计图找出来
Commander, tear this ship apart until you've found those plans...
把乘客带来！要活的！
and bring me the passengers! I want them alive!
那里有一个，设定为击晕模式
There's one. Set for stun.
她没事的
She'll be all right.
报告维达勋爵，我们抓到了一个囚犯
Inform Lord Vader we have a prisoner.
嘿，这里是不允许进入的，是禁区
Hey! You're not permitted in there. It's restricted.
你会失灵的
You'll be deactivated for sure.
不要嫌我嗦…
Don't you call me a mindless philosopher...
你不该去那里
you overweight glob of grease!
在别人看到你之前快出来吧
Now come out before somebody sees you.
秘密使命？什么计划？
Secret mission? What plans?
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
我不要进去
I'm not getting in there.
我一定会后悔的
I'm going to regret this.
又来了一个
There goes another one.
别开火，没有生命体
Hold your fire. There's no life forms.
里面一定是些铁家伙
It must have short-circuited.
真奇怪，损坏从这里看不是那么严重
That's funny. The damage doesn't look as bad from out here.
你确定这里安全吗？
Are you sure this thing is safe?
哦
Oh.
达斯・维德，只有你才会这么的胡作非为
Darth Vader. Only you could be so bold.
帝国参议院不会对此坐视不理的
The Imperial Senate will not sit still for this.
当他们知道你攻击了外交……
When they hear you've attacked a diplomatic...
不要装得这么惊讶，殿下
Don't act so surprised, Your Highness.
你可不是在干什么好事
You weren't on any mercy mission this time.
叛军的间谍向你们的飞船定向传输了若干信息
Several transmissions were beamed to this ship by rebel spies.
我想知道他们发送给你的那些计划是怎么回事
I want to know what happened to the plans they sent you.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
我是帝国参议院的成员…
I'm a member of the Imperial Senate...
去阿尔德兰执行一项外交任务
on a diplomatic mission to Alderaan.
你是叛军的一员，帝国的叛徒
You are part of the Rebel Alliance and a traitor.
把她带走
Take her away!
劫持她很危险
Holding her is dangerous.
如果事情传出去…
If word of this gets out...
可能在参议院中会产生对叛军的怜悯
it could generate sympathy for the rebellion in the senate.
种种迹象表明叛军间谍在和她联系
I've traced the rebel spies to her.
现在只有通过她才能找到他们的秘密基地
Now she is my only link to finding their secret base.
她死也不会说什么的
She'll die before she'll tell you anything.
都交给我吧
Leave that to me.
发出一个求救信号…
Send a distress signal...
然后告诉参议院所有船上的人都死了
and then inform the senate that all aboard were killed.
维德勋爵，死星的设计图…
Lord Vader, the battle station plans...
不在这艘飞船上…
are not aboard this ship...
而且并没有以其他方式传送走
and no transmissions were made.
刚刚一个逃生舱在战斗中被扔出飞船
An escape pod was jettisoned during the fighting...
但是没有发现里面有生命迹象
but no life forms were aboard.
她一定把计划藏在那个逃生舱了
She must have hidden the plans in the escape pod.
派一支部队去把它找回来，指挥官，在我个人看来
Send a detachment down to retrieve them... See to it personally, Commander.
这次不会有任何人阻止我们
There'll be no one to stop us this time.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
我们怎么这么倒霉？
How did we get into this mess?
我真不知是怎么回事
I really don't know how.
似乎有人安排我们去受苦一样
We seem to be made to suffer.
这就是我们的命运吧
It's our lot in life.
我必须休息一下不然就要散架了
I've got to rest before I fall apart.
我的关节就要冻结了
My joints are almost frozen.
这里真是个荒无人烟的地方！
What a desolate place this is!
你以为你在往哪里走？
Where do you think you're going?
我才不往那里走呢
Well, I'm not going that way.
那里太多岩石了
It's much too rocky.
这边的看起来好走许多
This way is much easier.
你怎么会觉得…
What makes you think...
那里会有住人的地方呢？
there are settlements over there?
别和我谈什么技术
Don't get technical with me.
什么任务？你在说什么？
What mission? What are you talking about?
我受够你了
I've just about had enough of you.
你往那里走吧
Go that way.
不到一天你就会失灵的…
You'll be malfunctioning within a day...
你这个目光短浅的废铜烂铁
you nearsighted scrap pile.
而且别让我发现你跟着我祈求帮助
And don't let me catch you following me begging for help...
因为我是绝不会帮你的
because you won't get it.
我不要冒险
No more adventures.
我不走那条路
I'm not going that way.
那个该死的蠢货
That malfunctioning little twerp.
这都是他的错
This is all his fault.
是他把我骗到这条路来的…
He tricked me into going this way...
但是他也不会好到哪里去
but he'll do no better.
等一下！那是什么？
Wait! What's that?
一个运输车
A transport.
我得救了
I'm saved!
在这里！
Over here!
嘿！
Hey!
救命！请救救我！
Help! Please help!
R2？
R2?
R2-D2，是你！是你！
R2-D2, it is you! It is you!
逃生舱里曾经有人
Someone was in the pod.
是往这个方向走的
The tracks go off in this direction.
看，长官，是机器人
Look, sir, droids.
我们停下来了
We stopped.
起来！起来！
Wake up! Wake up!
我们死定了
We're doomed.
你觉得他们会把我们F了吗？
Do you think they'll melt us down?
别开枪！别开枪！
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
什么时候才能结束呀？
Will this never end?
好吧，我们走
All right, fine. Let's go.
卢克！卢克！
Luke! Luke!
卢克，告诉你叔叔，如果他买一个会翻译的机器人
Luke, tell Uncle if he gets a translator...
一定要懂波西才行
be sure it speaks Bocce.
我们看起来没有太多的选择，我会告诉他的
Doesn't look like we have much of a choice, but I'll remind him.
好，我就要那个红色的
Yeah, we'll take that red one.
不，不是那个
No, not that one.
我想你是被用于行使繁文缛节的
I suppose you're programmed for etiquette and protocol.
什么意思？这是我的主要功能，先生
Protocol? Why, it's my primary function, sir.
我对于所有的风俗习惯都了如指掌…
I am well-versed in all the customs...
我不需要你这样的机器人
I have no need for a protocol droid.
你当然不需要了，先生
Of course you haven't, sir.
在这样的环境中是不需要的
Not in an environment such as this.
这就是为什么我已计划…
That is why I have been programmed...
我只需要一个机器人能够懂得…
What I really need is a droid who understands...
水蒸气蒸发器的二进制语言
the binary language of moisture vaporators.
蒸发器？先生，我的首要任务是操纵二进制货物起重机…
Vaporators? Sir, my first job was programming binary load lifters...
在各个方面都和你的蒸发器很类似
very similar to your vaporators in most respects.
你懂波西语吗？
Can you speak Bocce?
我当然懂了，先生，它就像是我的第二语言一样
Of course I can, sir. It's like a second language to me...
好吧，你闭嘴吧，我要这个了
Yeah, all right. Shut up. I'll take this one.
卢克！
Luke!
把这两个带到仓库去，好吗？
Take these two over to the garage, will you?
在午饭前把它们洗干净
I want them cleaned up before dinner.
但是我要去托西空间站呢
But I was going into Tosche Station...
去拿一些电整流器
to pick up some power converters.
只要把家里的事情做完
You can waste time with your friends...
我随便你和你的朋友们怎么浪费时间
when your chores are done.
现在快干活吧，把它搞好
Now come on. Get to it.
好吧，来吧
All right. Come on.
还有那个红色的，过来！
And the red one. Come on.
嘿，快来，那个红色的，我们走
Well, come on, red. Let's go.
欧文叔叔！
Uncle Owen!
什么事？
Yeah?
这个R2的发动机坏了，看！
This R2 unit has a bad motivator. Look.
嘿，看看你们卖给我们什么烂玩意！
Hey, what are you trying to push on us?
打扰一下，先生…
Excuse me, sir...
那个R2的情况非常好，绝对是笔好买卖
but that R2 unit is in prime condition, a real bargain.
欧文叔叔，那个怎么样？
Uncle Owen, what about that one?
那个蓝色的如何？
What about that blue one?
我们要那个了
We'll take that one.
把它拿走
Take this away.
你一定会对他满意的，先生
You'll be very pleased with that one, sir.
他的状态绝对是一流的
He really is in first-class condition.
我以前和他共事过
I've worked with him before.
他来了
Here he comes.
好吧，我们走
O.K. Let's go.
现在，你可不要忘了这事
Now, don't you forget this.
为什么我要为你卖命
Why I should stick my neck out for you...
这可不是我该做的
is quite beyond my capacity.
感谢造物主！
Thank the maker!
油浴实在是太舒服了
This oil bath is going to feel so good.
沙土的侵蚀让我的情况很不好
I've got such a bad case of dust contamination...
我都快不能动了
I can barely move.
太不公平了
It just isn't fair.
诶，毕格斯是对的
Oh, Biggs is right.
我永远都不能离开这里
I'm never gonna get out of here.
我可以帮上什么忙吗？
Is there anything I might do to help?
你帮不了我，除非你能改变时间
No. Not unless you can alter time...
加快收获的速度，或者把我传送出这个乱石堆
speed up the harvest, or teleport me off this rock.
恐怕我不能，先生
I don't think so, sir.
我只是一个机器人
I'm only a droid...
对于这方面的知识不太了解
and not very knowledgeable about such things...
至少在这个星球上
not on this planet, anyway.
事实上，我都不知道我在哪个星球上
As a matter of fact, I'm not even sure which planet I'm on.
嗯，如果宇宙中有一个明亮的中心的话
Well, if there's a bright center to the universe...
你就在离它最远的那个星球上
you're on the planet that it's farthest from.
我明白了，先生
I see, sir.
你可以叫我卢克
You can call me Luke.
我明白，卢克先生
I see, Sir Luke.
哈哈
Ha ha.
只要卢克就行了
Just Luke.
哦…我是C-3PO仿人类机器人
Oh... And I am C-3PO, human-cyborg relations.
这是我的伙伴，R2-D2
This is my counterpart... R2-D2.
你好
Hello.
你有很多碳化磨痕
You got a lot of carbon scoring.
看起来你们两个参与了不少行动
Looks like you boys have seen a lot of action.
经过了我们所经历的一切…
With all we've been through...
有时连我自己都很惊讶，我们居然能保持这么好的状态
sometimes I'm amazed we're in as good condition as we are...
和反抗军他们在一起共事
what with the rebellion and all.
你们认识对抗帝国的反抗军？
You know of the rebellion against the Empire?!
不然我们也不会被卖到你这里来…
That's how we came to be in your service...
如果你懂我的意思的话，先生
if you take my meaning, sir.
你们经历过很多战役吗？
Have you been in many battles?
一些，我想
Several, I think.
事实上，我没有太多的要说
Actually, there's not much to tell.
我只不过是一个翻译者…
I'm not much more than an interpreter...
并不太善于说故事
and not very good at telling stories.
嗯，确切地说不能把故事说得有趣些
Well, not at making them interesting, anyway.
我的小朋友…
Well, my little friend...
有个东西塞在这里了
you got something jammed in here real good.
你们到过帝国战舰或是…
Were you on a Starcruiser or...
帮帮我，欧比旺・科诺比，你是我唯一的希望
Help me, Obi-Wan Kenobi. You're my only hope.
这是什么
What's this?
快回答，他在问你问题呢
"What is what"? He asked you a question.
那是什么？
What is that?
帮帮我，欧比旺・科诺比
Help me, Obi-Wan Kenobi.
你是我唯一的希望
You're my only hope.
帮帮我，欧比旺・科诺比
Help me, Obi-Wan Kenobi.
你是我唯一的希望
You're my only hope.
他说这什么都不是，先生，只是一次故障
He says it's nothing, sir, merely a malfunction.
旧的数据，不要理它
Old data. Pay it no mind.
她是谁？她可真漂亮
Who is she? She's beautiful.
我不太清楚，先生
I'm afraid I'm not quite sure, sir.
我想她是我们上次一旅途中的一名乘客
I think she was a passenger on our last voyage.
一个不重要的人，我认为
A person of some importance, I believe.
我们的船长和……
Our captain was attached...
这个录像还有其他部分吗？
Is there any more to this recording?
表现一下自己呀，R2
Behave yourself, R2.
你这样会给我们惹麻烦的
You're going to get us into trouble.
没事的，你可以信任他，他现在是我们的新主人
It's all right. You can trust him. He's our new master.
他说他属于附近的一个居民…
He says that he's the property of Obi-Wan Kenobi...
名叫欧比旺・科诺比…
a resident of these parts...
而且这是给欧比旺的私人信息
and it's a private message for him.
坦白地说，先生，我并不知道他在说什么
Quite frankly, sir, I don't know what he's talking about.
我们上一个主人是安德烈斯船长
Our last master was Captain Antilles.
但是经过一些事情以后…
But with all we've been through...
这个小机器人变得有些古怪了
this little R2 unit has become a bit eccentric.
欧比旺・科诺比，我想会不会是说本・科诺比
Obi-Wan Kenobi. I wonder if he means old Ben Kenobi.
请再说一边，先生，你知道他在说什么吗？
I beg your pardon, sir, but do you know what he's talking about?
我不认识什么欧比旺…
I don't know any Obi-Wan...
本住在沙丘之海的那一头
but old Ben lives out beyond the Dune Sea.
他是一个奇怪的隐士
He's kind of a strange old hermit.
帮帮我，欧比旺・科诺比
Help me, Obi-Wan Kenobi.
我在想她是谁
I wonder who she is.
听起来她好像有麻烦
Sounds like she's in trouble.
我最好从头看一边
I better play back the whole thing.
他说限制螺栓…
He says the restraining bolt...
把他的影像系统给短路了
has short-circuited his recording system.
他建议如果你能把那个螺栓拿掉…
He suggests that if you remove the bolt...
他可能可以为你播放全部的影像
he might be able to play back the entire recording.
哦，好吧…
Oh, yeah. Well...
我想你们两个是不能从我手里逃掉的
I guess you're too small to run away on me...
如果我把它拿掉的话
if I take this off.
好吧…
OK...
好了
There you go.
等一下，她去那里了
Wait a minute. Where'd she go?
把她放出来，播放全部的影像！
Bring her back. Play back the entire message.
"什么影像"？
"What message"?
你刚刚放的那个
The one you've just been playing!
你这个修铁罐里面存着的
The one you're carrying inside your rusty innards.
卢克！卢克！
Luke! Luke!
好的，我马上就到，贝鲁阿姨
All right, I'll be right there, Aunt Beru.
对不起…
I'm sorry, sir...
他好像受到一点扰动
but he appears to have picked up a slight flutter.
拿着，看看你能做些什么
Here. See what you can do with him.
我马上就回来
I'll be right back.
你还是考虑一下是否播放给他看吧
Just you reconsider playing that message for him.
我想他一点都不喜欢你
No, I don't think he likes you at all.
我也不喜欢你
No, I don't like you, either.
我觉得我们买来的R2机器人可能是偷来的
You know, I think that R2 unit we bought might have been stolen.
你怎么会这么想？
What makes you think that?
我在清洗他的时候无意中搞出一段录像
Well, I stumbled across a recording while I was cleaning him.
他说他属于一个叫欧比旺・科诺比的人
He says he belongs to someone called Obi-Wan Kenobi.
我想他也许是在说本
I thought he might have meant old Ben.
你知道他说的是什么吗？
Do you know what he's talking about?
呃
Mm-mm.
我想他和本有关
I wonder if he's related to Ben.
那个巫师只是一个疯老头子
That wizard's just a crazy old man.
明天你把那个R2带到锚头城那里去
Tomorrow, I want you to take that R2 unit to Anchorhead...
把他的内存清空
and have its memory erased.
这样就结束了，他现在属于我们
That'll be the end of it. It belongs to us now.
如果这个欧比旺来找他怎么办？
But what if this Obi-Wan comes looking for him?
他不会的
He won't.
我不认为他还活着
I don't think he exists any more.
他和你父亲差不多一个时候去世的
He died about the same time as your father.
他认识我的父亲？
He knew my father?
我告诉你忘了这件事
I told you to forget it.
你现在需要考虑的是让这些新机器人明天开始干活
Your only concern is to prepare those new droids for tomorrow.
明天一早，我希望看到他们在南边的山头上
In the morning, I want them up there on the south ridge...
操纵那些压缩机
working on those condensers.
好的
Yes, sir.
我想那些机器人工作会顺利的
I think those new droids are gonna work out fine.
事实上，我也在想我们协定
In fact, I, uh, was also thinking about our agreement...
有关我再呆一个季节的事情
about me staying on another season?
如果这些新的机器人能够工作…
And if these new droids do work out...
我想今年就向学院发出申请
I want to transmit my application to the academy this year.
你是说在收获前的那个学期？
You mean the next semester before the harvest?
当然，这里的机器人绰绰有余
Sure. There's more than enough droids.
收获是我最需要你的时候
Harvest is when I need you the most.
只不过多干一个季度
It's only one season more.
今年收获应该足够…
This year we'll make enough on the harvest...
以后就可以雇佣更多的人手…
that I'll be able to hire more hands...
这样，明年你就可以去学院了
and then you can go to the academy next year.
你必须要理解，我这里很需要你，卢克
You must understand I need you here, Luke.
但是，这又是一整年
But it's a whole 'nother year!
只是多干一个季度
Look, it's only one more season.
是呀，毕格斯和谭克离开的时候，你也是这么说的
Yeah, that's what you said when Biggs and Tank left.
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
谁都看得出我哪都去不了
Looks like I'm going nowhere.
我去把那些机器人洗完
I have to go finish cleaning those droids.
欧文，他不能一直呆在这里
Owen, he can't stay here forever.
大多数他的朋友都离开了
Most of his friends have gone.
这对于他来说很重要
It means so much to him.
我明年会满足他的
I'll make it up to him next year.
我保证
I promise.
卢克可不只是一个农民，欧文
Luke's just not a farmer, Owen.
他有太多的地方和他的父亲一样
He has too much of his father in him.
这也正是我所担心的
That's what I'm afraid of.
哦！
Ooh!
你躲在后面干什么？
What are you doing hiding back there?
这不是我的错，先生，求你不要关掉我
It wasn't my fault, sir. Please don't deactivate me.
我告诉他不要走，但是他似乎出了故障
I told him not to go, but he's faulty, malfunctioning.
一直都在嘀咕他的任务
Kept babbling on about his mission.
哦，不
Oh, no.
那个R2机器人一直都有点问题
That R2 unit has always been a problem.
这些航天机器人常常无法控制
These astrodroids are getting quite out of hand.
即使是我也常常不能理解他的逻辑
Even I can't understand their logic at times.
他怎么能这么愚蠢？
How could I be so stupid?
他不在视野之内
He's nowhere in sight.
真该死！
Blast it!
对不起，先生，我们可以去追他吗？
Pardon me, sir, but couldn't we go after him?
太危险了，到处都是沙人
It's too dangerous with all the Sandpeople around.
我们必须要等到早晨
We'll have to wait until morning.
卢克！我要关闭电源了
Luke! I'm shutting the power down.
好的！我马上就回来
All right! I'll be there in a few minutes.
我一定会把他找回来的
Boy, am I gonna get it.
那个小机器人会给我惹很多麻烦的
That little droid's going to cause me a lotta trouble.
他最擅长这个了，先生
Oh, he excels at that, sir.
来吧
Come on.
卢克？
Luke?
卢克！
Luke!
你今天早晨看到卢克了吗？
Have you seen Luke this morning?
他说在今天开始干活前有些事要做…
He said he had some things to do before he started today...
所以他要早点走
so he left early.
他把那两个新机器人也带上了？
Did he take those two new droids with him?
我想是的
I think so.
好吧，他最好在中午之前
Well, he better have those units in the south range...
把那两个机器人修好送到南边的山头去，不然那里就要多花很多钱了
repaired by midday, or there'll be hell to pay.
看，在扫描器上有一个机器人
Lookit, there's a droid on the scanner.
直向前
Dead ahead.
可能是我们的R2机器人，按加速器！
It might be our little R2 unit. Hit the accelerator!
嘿，停下！你要去哪里？
Hey, whoa! Where do you think you're going?
卢克主人现在是你的合法拥有者
Master Luke is your rightful owner now.
不要再说什么欧比旺・科努比之类的东西
We'll have no more of this Obi-Wan Kenobi gibberish.
也不要再和我说什么你的任务
And don't talk to me of your mission, either.
你该感到很幸运
You're fortunate he doesn't blast you...
他没有向你射击把你打成碎片
into a million pieces right here!
不，没事的，但是我想我们最好还是走吧
No. It's all right, but I think we'd better go.
他现在又怎么了？
What's wrong with him now?
有若干生物从东南方向向我们逼近
There are several creatures approaching from the southeast.
沙人，或是更糟
Sandpeople, or worse.
来，我们去看一看
Come on. Let's go have a look.
来呀！
Come on!
下面有两头本莎…
Well, there are two Banthas down there...
但是没看到… 等一下
but I don't see any... Wait a second.
是沙人，没错
They're Sandpeople, all right.
我能看到他们其中一个
I can see one of them now.
你好啊
Hello, there.
过来，我的小朋友，不要害怕
Come here, my little friend. Don't be afraid.
别担心，他没事的
Oh, don't worry. He'll be all right.
你没事了，小伙子，你今天似乎很忙呀
Rest easy, son. You've had a busy day.
你很幸运你还是一整块
You're fortunate to be all in one piece.
本？
Ben?
本・科诺比？
Ben Kenobi?
伙计，我很高兴见到你
Boy, am I glad to see you.
到这里来应该多带些武器
The Jundland Wastes are not to be traveled lightly.
告诉我，年轻的卢克…
Tell me, young Luke...
为什么来这么远的地方？
what brings you out this far?
这个小机器人
This little droid.
我想他正在寻找他以前的主人…
I think he's searching for his former master...
我从来没有见过这么忠诚的机器人
but I've never seen such devotion in a droid before.
他说自己属于…
He claims to be the property...
一个叫欧比旺・科努比的人
of an Obi-Wan Kenobi.
他是你的亲戚吗？
Is he a relative of yours?
你知道他说的是谁吗？
Do you know who he's talking about?
欧比旺・科诺比？
Obi-Wan Kenobi?
欧比旺
Obi-Wan.
这个名字我有很久没有听到过了
Now, that's a name I've not heard in a long time.
很久很久
A long time.
我想我的叔叔认识他
I think my uncle knows him.
他说他死了
He said he was dead.
他并没有死
Oh, he's not dead.
还没有
Not yet.
你认识他？
You know him?
哦，我当然认识他，那个人就是我
Well, of course I know him. He's me.
我自从你出生前…
I haven't gone by the name of Obi-Wan...
就不用欧比旺这个名字了
since, oh, before you were born.
看来这个机器人确实属于你
Well, then the droid does belong to you.
我不记得曾经拥有过一个机器人
I don't seem to remember ever owning a droid.
非常的有趣
Very interesting.
我想我们最好到室内去
I think we better get indoors.
沙人很容易被吓跑…
The Sandpeople are easily startled...
但是他们很快就会回来，而且数量更多
but they'll soon be back, and in greater numbers.
3PO
3PO.
我在哪里？我刚才一定是踏错地方了
Where am I? I must have taken a bad step.
你能站起来吗？
Can you stand?
我们必须在沙人回来之前离开这里
We've got to get out of here before the Sandpeople return.
我想我不行的，你走吧，卢克主人
I don't think I can make it. You go on, Master Luke.
你不能为了我威胁到自己的安全
There's no sense in you risking yourself on my account.
我真是不中用
I'm done for.
不，你不是的
No, you're not.
说这个算什么？
What kind of talk is that?
快点，他们就快来了
Quickly. They're on the move.
不，我的父亲没有打过仗
No, my father didn't fight in the wars.
他是香料货船的领航员
He was a navigator on a spice freighter.
这是你叔叔告诉你的
That's what your uncle told you.
他不赞同你父亲的理想
He didn't hold with your father's ideals.
他想呆在这里…
Thought he should have stayed here...
与世无争
and not gotten involved.
你曾经参与过克隆人战争？
You fought in the Clone Wars?
是的，我曾是一名绝地武士…
Yes. I was once a Jedi knight...
和你的父亲一样
the same as your father.
我真希望能够了解他
I wish I'd known him.
他曾是银河中最好的星际飞行员…
He was the best starpilot in the galaxy...
是一名睿智的战士
and a cunning warrior.
我能理解你已经成为…
I understand you've become...
一名优秀的飞行员
quite a good pilot yourself.
他也曾是我的好朋友
And he was a good friend.
这提醒了我
Which reminds me...
有些东西要给你
I have something here for you.
你的父亲要我把这个给你…
Your father wanted you to have this...
当你长大了的时候…
when you were old enough...
但是你的叔叔是不会允许的
but your uncle wouldn't allow it.
他害怕你跟随老欧比 旺…
He feared you might follow old Obi-Wan...
投身那些愚蠢的理想化的正义运动…
on some damn-fool idealistic crusade...
就像你的父亲一样
like your father did.
先生，如果你暂时不需要我
Sir, if you'll not be needing me...
我先关闭一会
I'll close down for a while.
好，没问题
Sure. Go ahead.
这是什么？
What is it?
这是你父亲的光剑
It's your father's lightsaber.
这是绝地武士的武器
This is the weapon of a Jedi knight.
不像激光枪那样的笨重和不稳定
Not as clumsy or random as a blaster.
是文明时代中的一种优雅的武器
An elegant weapon for a more civilized age.
绝地武士在旧的共和国中
For over a thousand generations...
是和平与公正的卫士
the Jedi knights were the guardians...
这持续了几千代人
of peace and justice in the old Republic...
直到黑暗时代的到来…
before the dark times...
直到帝国的诞生
before the Empire.
我的父亲是怎么死的
How did my father die?
一个年轻的名叫达斯・维德的绝地武士…
A young Jedi named Darth Vader...
在他投身黑暗势力之前是我的学生
who was a pupil of mine until he turned to evil...
帮助帝国追捕猎杀绝地武士
helped the Empire hunt down and destroy the Jedi knights.
他背叛了你的父亲，并且谋杀了他
He betrayed and murdered your father.
现在绝地武士几乎灭绝
Now the Jedi are all but extinct.
维德被“原力”的黑暗的一面所引诱
Vader was seduced by the dark side of the Force.
“原力”？
The Force?
“原力”是绝地武士力量的源泉
The Force is what gives a Jedi his power.
是一种力场，由所有的所有的生物所产生
It's an energy field created by all living things.
它包围的我们，穿透着我们…
It surrounds us, penetrates us...
他让银河紧密地联系在一起
it binds the galaxy together.
现在让我们看看你是怎么一回事，小朋友
Now let's see if we can't figure out what you are, my little friend...
你从哪里来
and where you come from.
我看过部分信息…
I saw part of a message he was...
我应该已经找到了
I seem to have found it.
科诺比将军，多年前在克隆人战争中，你曾为我的父亲效力
General Kenobi, years ago you served my father in the Clone Wars.
现在，他祈求你的帮助
Now he begs you to help him...
以对付帝国
in his struggle against the Empire.
我很抱歉我无法亲自向你呈上我父亲的请求
I regret that I am unable to present my father's request to you in person.
我的飞船正在遭受攻击…
But my ship has fallen under attack...
恐怕我把你带到阿尔德兰的计划要失败了
and I am afraid my mission to bring you to Alderaan has failed.
我有对于反抗军的生死存亡至关重要的信息…
I have placed information vital to the survival of the rebellion...
存在了这个R2机器人的内存里
into the memory systems of this R2 unit.
我的父亲会知道怎么复原的
My father will know how to retrieve it.
你一定要把这个机器人…
You must see this droid...
安全的送到阿尔德兰
safely delivered to him on Alderaan.
这是我们最绝望的时刻
This is our most desperate hour.
帮帮我，欧比旺・科诺比，你是我唯一的希望
Help me, Obi-Wan Kenobi. You're my only hope.
你必须要学学使用“原力”的方法
You must learn the ways of the Force...
如果你和我去阿尔德兰的话
if you're to come with me to Alderaan.
阿尔德兰？我不去阿尔德兰
Alderaan? I'm not going to Alderaan.
我要回家
I've got to get home.
很晚了，我只能做这么多了
It's late. I'm in for it as it is.
我需要你的帮助，卢克，她也需要你的帮助
I need your help, Luke. She needs your help.
对于这种事情来说我已经老了
I'm getting too old for this sort of thing.
我不该卷入的
I can't get involved.
我还有工作要做
I've got work to do.
不是我说喜欢帝国，我憎恨它
It's not that I like the Empire. I hate it...
但是我现在什么都做不了
but there's nothing I can do about it right now.
而且到那里有很远的一段路
It's all such a long way from here.
这是你叔叔的口气
That's your uncle talking.
我的叔叔
My uncle.
我该怎么解释这个？
How am I ever gonna explain this?
学习使用“原力”吧，卢克
Learn about the Force, Luke.
最远我可以把你送到锚头城
Look, I can take you as far as Anchorhead.
在那里你可以换乘运输机去莫斯艾斯利，或者其他任何你想去的地方
You can get a transport there to Mos Eisley or wherever you're going.
当然，你必须做你认为对的事情
You must do what you feel is right, of course.
在这个武装空间站正常工作以前
Until this battle station is fully operational...
我们都是非常脆弱的
we are vulnerable.
叛军联盟的武器非常的精良
The Rebel Alliance is too well equipped.
他们比你们想象的更危险
They're more dangerous than you realize.
对你的舰队来说是危险的，指挥官
Dangerous to your starfleet, Commander...
对这个武装空间站来说可算不上什么
not to this battle station.
叛军会继续获取支持…
The rebellion will continue to gain support...
从帝国参议院那里…
in the Imperial Senate...
我们再也不用去理会什么帝国参议院了
The Imperial Senate will no longer be of any concern to us.
我刚刚收到的消息
I have just received word...
陛下已经永久的解除了议会
that the emperor has dissolved the council permanently.
旧共和国的最后一点残余…
The last remnants of the old Republic...
终于被扫除了
have been swept away.
这不可能
That's impossible.
陛下没有官僚机构怎么统治整个帝国
How will the emperor maintain control without the bureaucracy?
地方统治者有直接控制权…
The regional governors now have direct control...
所有他们管辖的区域
over their territories.
恐惧，将使地方星系秩序井然…
Fear will keep the local systems in line...
对于这个武装空间站的恐惧
fear of this battle station.
那么叛军怎么办？
And what of the rebellion?
如果叛军获取了
If the rebels have obtained...
这个空间站全面的技术信息
a complete technical readout of this station...
很有可能性，虽然不太可能成功
it is possible, however unlikely...
他们找到这里的一个弱点然后进行利用它
that they might find a weakness and exploit it.
你所提到的这个设计图很快就将落入我们的手中
The plans you refer to will soon be back in our hands.
叛军对于这个空间站任何的攻击…
Any attack made by the rebels against this station...
都将是毫无意义的行动…
would be a useless gesture...
无论他们获取到什么技术信息
no matter what technical data they've obtained.
这个空间站现在是宇宙中的终极力量
This station is now the ultimate power in the universe.
我建议我们利用它
I suggest we use it.
不要过分的骄傲…
Don't be too proud...
关于你建造的这个技术玩意
of this technological terror you've constructed.
摧毁一个行星的能力
The ability to destroy a planet is insignificant...
和“原力”比起来实在是不算什么
next to the power of the Force.
不要试图用你的巫师技巧来吓唬我，维达勋爵
Don't try to frighten us with your sorcerer's ways, Lord Vader.
你对于那个古老的信仰的忠诚…
Your sad devotion to that ancient religion...
没能帮你召唤回丢失的磁带…
hasn't helped you conjure up the stolen data tapes...
也没有给你足够的洞察力…
or given you clairvoyance enough...
去发现叛军的秘密基地…
to find the rebels' hidden fortre...
我对你的不敬非常的不满意
I find your lack of faith disturbing.
够了！维德，放开他
Enough of this. Vader, release him.
听你的
As you wish.
这种争吵是无意义的
This bickering is pointless.
维达勋爵在这个空间站正常运作之前…
Lord Vader will provide us with the location of the rebel fortress...
会向我们提供叛军基地的地址的
by the time this station is operational.
然后我们就去进攻叛军…
We will then crush the rebellion...
要一击致命
with one swift stroke.
看起来是沙人干的
It looks like the Sandpeople did this, all right.
看，这里有手杖，本莎的脚印
Look. There's gaffi sticks, Bantha tracks.
只是，我从来没有听说……
It's just, I've never heard of them...
他们会攻击这么大的家伙
hitting anything this big before.
不是他们干的
They didn't...
是有人要让我们相信沙人做的
but we are meant to think they did.
这些痕迹两边都有的
These tracks are side-by-side.
沙人总是一列纵队
Sandpeople always ride single file...
来隐藏他们的数量
to hide their numbers.
这和卖给我们R2和3PO的爪哇人人一样
These are the same Jawas that sold us R2 and 3PO.
而且，这些爆破点过于精确
And these blast points, too accurate...
对于沙人来说
for Sandpeople.
只有帝国的突击队能够这么精确
Only imperial stormtroopers are so precise.
为什么帝国部队要屠杀爪哇人？
But why would imperial troops want to slaughter Jawas?
如果他们跟踪机器人到这里…
If they traced the robots here...
他们可能知道机器人被卖到…
they may have learned who they sold them to...
这样就把他们引到了… 家！
and that would lead them back... home!
等等， 卢克！
Wait, Luke!
太危险了
It's too dangerous!
欧文叔叔
Uncle Owen!
贝鲁婶婶
Aunt Beru!
欧文叔叔
Uncle Owen!
现在，殿下…
And now, Your Highness...
让我们来谈谈有关…
we will discuss the location...
你们叛军的秘密基地的地址吧
of your hidden rebel base.
你真么都做不了的，卢克…
There's nothing you could have done, Luke...
如果你在那里的话
had you been there.
你也会被杀掉…
You'd have been killed, too...
而且这两个机器人就落入了帝国的手中
and the droids would now be in the hands of the Empire.
我要和你一起去阿尔德兰
I want to come with you to Alderaan.
我在这里什么都没有了
There's nothing for me here now.
我要学习使用“原力”的方法…
I want to learn the ways of the Force...
像我父亲一样成为一名绝地武士
and become a Jedi like my father.
莫斯埃斯利机场
Mos Eisley spaceport.
你找不到比这里更糟的藏污纳垢的地方了
You will never find a more wretched hive of scum and villainy.
我们必须要小心
We must be cautious.
你们拥有这两个机器人多久了
How long have you had these droids?
3或4个季度
Three or four seasons.
如果你们需要可以卖给你们
They're up for sale if you want them.
让我看看你们的证件
Let me see your identification.
你不需要看他的证件
You don't need to see his identification.
我们不需要看他的证件
We don't need to see his identification.
这些不是你要找的机器人
These aren't the droids you're looking for.
这些不是我们要找的机器人
These aren't the droids we're looking for.
他能去忙自己的事情了
He can go about his business.
你去忙自己的事情吧
You can go about your business.
开走
Move along.
我不能忍受那些爪哇人人，恶心的生物
I can't abide those Jawas. Disgusting creatures!
走开，走开
Go on, go on.
我不知道我们怎么混过那些卫兵的
I can't understand how we got by those troops.
我以为我们死定了
I thought we were dead.
“原力”对于那些意志不坚定的人
The Force can have a strong influence...
可以产生很强大的影响
on the weak-minded.
你真的认为在这里可以找到一名飞行员
Do you really think we're gonna find a pilot here...
把我们送到阿尔德兰吗？
that'll take us to Alderaan?
多数优秀的飞行员都在这里出没…
Most of the best freighter pilots are to be found here...
只是你要小心一点
only watch your step.
这个地方可能有点危险
This place can be a little rough.
我都准备好了
I'm ready for anything.
来吧，R2
Come along, R2.
嘿！这玩意我们不接待！
Hey! We don't serve their kind here.
什么？
What?
你的机器人，他们必须在外面等着
Your droids, they'll have to wait outside.
他们不让进
We don't want them here.
不如你们去车上等我们吧
Why don't you wait out by the speeder?
我们不想惹麻烦
We don't want any trouble.
我同意，先生
I heartily agree with you, sir.
呃…
Uh...
给我来一杯
I'll have one of those.
他不喜欢你
He doesn't like you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我也不喜欢你
I don't like you, either.
你可要小心一点
You just watch yourself.
我们可是逃犯
We're wanted men.
我在12个星系里被判了死刑
I have the death sentence on 12 systems.
我会小心的
I'll be careful.
我要杀了你
You'll be dead!
对这个小家伙不值得这样
This little one's not worth the effort.
来，我给你买一杯吧
Come, let me get you something.
啊！
Aah!
我没事
I'm all right.
这是楚贝卡，一架飞船的副驾驶…
Chewbacca here is first mate...
也许能载我们
on a ship that might suit us.
我可不喜欢这样
I don't like the look of this.
汉 索罗，我是千年鹰号的船长
Han Solo. I'm captain of the Millennium Falcon.
楚伊告诉我你们需要搭乘去阿尔德兰星系
Chewie here tells me you're looking for passage to the Alderaan system.
是的，没错，如果你的飞船足够块的话
Yes, indeed, if it's a fast ship.
足够快？你从来没有听说过千年鹰号？
Fast ship? You've never heard of the Millennium Falcon?
我应该听过吗？
Should I have?
不到12秒差就能到达开索
It's the ship that made the Kessel run in less than 12 parsecs.
我曾成功逃脱过帝国战舰的追捕
I've outrun imperial starships.
提醒你一下，不是什么当地的那些破飞船
Not the local bulk cruisers, mind you.
我说的是大的凯若里战舰
I'm talking about the big Corellian ships now.
而且，老头子，对于你来说，足够快了
She's fast enough for you, old man.
运什么货？
What's the cargo?
只有乘客… 我自己，这个孩子…
Only passengers... myself, the boy...
还有两个机器人…
two droids...
还有，不要问任何问题
and no questions asked.
是什么呀？在当地遇到麻烦了？
What is it, some kind of local trouble?
按我的话说，我们是要躲避…
Let's just say we'd like to avoid...
帝国军的纠缠
any imperial entanglements.
好，这才是重头戏
Well, that's the real trick, isn't it?
而且，为了这个我要多收钱的
And it's gonna cost you something extra.
10,000，全部提前支付
10,000, all in advance.
10,000？
10,000?
我们都可以买自己的飞船了
We could almost buy our own ship for that!
但是，谁来给你们开呢？小子，你吗？
But who's gonna fly it, kid, you?
我想我可以，我是个不错的飞行员
You bet I could. I'm not such a bad pilot myself.
我们不要坐在这里听他说…
We don't have to sit here and listen...
我现在可以付给你2，000…
We can pay you 2,000 now...
到阿尔德兰以后再加15，000
plus 15 when we reach Alderaan.
17,000，对吗？
Seventeen, huh?
好的，你们找到你们要的船了
O.K. You guys got yourselves a ship.
你们一准备好我们就出发
We'll leave as soon as you're ready.
94号停机坪
Docking Bay 94.
九十四
Ninety-four.
看起来似乎有人开始对你刚才的那一剑感兴趣了
Looks like somebody's beginning to take an interest in your handiwork.
好的，我们去检查一下
All right. We'll check it out.
17，000！
17,000!
这些人一定是走投无路了
Those guys must really be desperate.
这些钱可救了我一命
This could really save my neck.
回到船上去，做好准备
Get back to the ship, get it ready.
你必须把你的车卖了
You'll have to sell your speeder.
没问题，我以后再也不回这里了
That's O.K. I'm never coming back to this planet again.
要离开吗，索罗？
Going somewhere, Solo?
是的，格里多
Yes, Greedo.
事实上，我刚准备去见你的老板
As a matter of fact, I was just going to see your boss.
告诉贾巴我现在有钱了
Tell Jabba that I've got his money.
太晚了
It's too late.
你已经失去那个机会了
You should have paid him when you had the chance.
贾巴悬赏了一大笔钱要你的人头…
Jabba's put a price on your head so large...
银河中所有的赏金猎人都在找你
every bounty hunter in the galaxy will be looking for you.
我很幸运第一个找到你
I'm lucky I found you first.
但是，这一次我有钱了
Yeah, but this time I've got the money.
如果你把钱给我，我可以忘掉这次会面
If you give it to me, I might forget I found you.
钱不再我身上
I don't have it with me.
告诉贾巴…
Tell Jabba...
贾巴看透你了
Jabba's through with you.
对那些一看到帝国舰队就丢掉货物的走私贩
He has no time for smugglers...
贾巴懒得理他们
who drop their shipments at the first sign of an imperial cruiser.
我有时也会失手
Even I get boarded sometimes.
你认为我有选择吗？
Do you think I had a choice?
你可以自己和贾巴说，他只能拿到你的船了
You can tell that to Jabba. He may only take your ship.
除非我死了
Over my dead body.
好主意
That's the idea.
我等这一刻很久了
I've been looking forward to this for a long time.
我想你是的
I'll bet you have.
抱歉添乱了
Sorry about the mess.
她对于意识探测器的抗拒非常强烈
Her resistance to the mind probe is considerable.
从她那里获取信息需要不少时间
It'll be some time before we can extract any information from her.
最终的检测完毕
The final checkout is completed.
所有的系统都正常运转
All systems are operational.
我们该设定什么轨道？
What course shall we set?
也许她屈服于…
Perhaps she would respond...
另一种劝降的方式
to an alternative form of persuasion.
你是什么意思？
What do you mean?
我想现在是时候展示…
I think it is time we demonstrated...
这个空间站最大火力了
the full power of this station.
设定轨道为阿尔德兰
Set your course for Alderaan.
好的
With pleasure.
把门锁起来，R2
Lock the door, R2.
检查一下街道的这边
Check this side of the street.
这个门锁了，去下一个
The door's locked. Move on to the next.
与和你待在这里相比
I would much rather have gone with Master Luke...
我更愿意去和卢克主人待在一起
than stay here with you.
我不知道这些麻烦到底是怎么回事…
I don't know what all this trouble is about...
但是我可以肯定这都是你的错
but I'm sure it must be your fault.
注意你的语言
You watch your language.
好吧，给我
All right. Give it to me. I'll take it.
看看这个
Look at this.
自从XP-38问世以后，他们就不太吃香了
Ever since the XP-38 came out, they just aren't in demand.
这些已经够了
It'll be enough.
索罗！出来吧，索罗！
Solo! Come out of there, Solo!
我在这里，贾巴
Right here, Jabba.
我一直在等你
I've been waitin' for you.
我总算找到你了
Have you now.
你不会以为我想跑吧，有吗？
You didn't think I was gonna run, did you?
汉，我的孩子，你太让我失望了
Han, my boy, you disappoint me.
为什么你还不还钱…
Why haven't you paid me...
为什么你杀死了可怜的格里多？
and why did you fry poor Greedo?
贾巴，如下次想找我谈话，你自己来找我
Look, Jabba, next time you want to talk to me, come see me yourself.
不要派那些废物来
Don't send one of these twerps.
汉，我不容许例外
Han, I can't make exceptions.
如果每个帮我运货的人
What if everyone who smuggled for me...
看见帝国的战舰撒腿就跑的话
dropped their cargo at the first sign...
那我还怎么做生意阿？
of an imperial starship?
这生意可不好做哦
It's not good business.
贾巴，就连我也会怕阿
Look, Jabba, even I get boarded sometimes.
你以为我还有别的选择吗？
You think I had a choice?
不过我有个很好的提议
But I got a nice, easy charter.
我会把钱还你的，一分不少还有得多
I'll pay ya back, plus a little extra.
只是我还需要一点时间
I just need a little more time.
你是最好的我知道
Han, my boy, you're the best.
那么就20%吧…
So, for an extra 20%...
十五，贾巴，最多了
Fifteen, Jabba. Don't push it.
好吧，15%
Okay, 15%.
但如果你这次又失败的话….
But if you fail me again...
我一定会通缉你..
I'll put a price on your head so big...
让你永远接近不了有人住的地方
you won't be able to go near a civilized system.
贾巴，你是我见过最好的人类
Jabba... you're a wonderful human being.
来吧
Come on!
如果这飞船像他讲得那样快的话….
If the ship's as fast as he's boasting...
我们应该可以成功
we ought to do well.
这是什么破东西啊！
What a piece of junk!
他可是光速的5倍哦
She'll make.5 past light speed.
他也许看起来不怎么样…
She may not look like much...
但是在关键的时候是挺管用的
but she's got it where it counts, kid.
我自己做过很多的调整
I've made a lot of special modifications myself.
但现在时间比较紧，你们如果可以上船的话
But we're a little rushed, so if you'll just get on board...
我们就要出发了
we'll get outta here.
你好，先生
Hello, sir.
往哪里？
Which way?
把弹药装上
All right, men, load your weapons.
把那船给我截下来，炸了它！
Stop that ship! Blast them!
楚伊，带我们走！
Chewie, get us out of here!
天哪，我最讨厌星际旅行了
Oh, my. I'd forgotten how much I hate space travel.
看来是帝国的巡洋舰
Looks like an imperial cruiser.
看来那些人是紧咬不放了
Our passengers must be hotter than I thought.
别让他们追上了
Try and hold 'em off.
把防护系统调好
Angle the deflector shields while I make the calculations...
我要做进入光速的准备程序
for the jump to light speed.
注意了，又有两架
Stay sharp. There's two more comin' in.
他们想要截住我们
They're gonna try and cut us off.
你为什么不加速阿？不是说这玩意儿很快吗！
Why don't you outrun 'em? I thought you said this thing was fast!
注意你说的话，要不你就不要跟着我们
Watch your mouth, kid, or you're gonna find yourself floating home.
只要进了外太空
We'll be safe enough...
我们就安全了
once we make the jump to hyperspace.
我可以甩掉他们
Besides, I know a few maneuvers. We'll lose 'em.
好戏就要开始了
Here's where the fun begins.
你什么时候才能上光速阿？
How long before you can make the jump to light speed?
我要先从计算机里得到我们坐标
It'll take a few moments to get the coordinates from the navicomputer.
你不回开玩笑吧？他们都快追上来了！
Are you kidding? At the rate they're gaining?
在外太空航行可不像你想象得那么简单！
Traveling through hyperspace ain't like dustin' crops, boy!
如果没有精确的计算…
Without precise calculations...
我们可能会撞上一颗恒星
we'd fly right through a star...
或是与一颗新行星擦身而过
or bounce too close to a supernova...
这样我们就没得玩了
and that would end your trip real quick, wouldn't it?
那闪光是什么？
What's that flashing?
我们的防护网要消失了
We're losing a deflector shield.
坐好了
Go strap yourselves in.
我们就要进入光速了
I'm gonna make the jump to light speed.
我们就要进入阿尔德兰了
We've entered the Alderaan system.
塔金行政官
Governor Tarkin.
我早就应该料到了
I should have expected...
是你在控制维德
to find you holding Vader's leash.
我从一上船
I recognized your foul stench...
就闻到了你的臭味
when I was brought on board.
到现在仍是这么迷人
Charming to the last.
你不知道我发现下达处决你的命令
You don't know how hard I found it...
心里有多难过
signing the order to terminate your life.
不过我很高兴
I'm surprised you had the courage...
你帮我下了这个决心
to take the responsibility yourself.
莉娅公主
Princess Leia, before your execution...
在你被处决之前
I would like you to be my guest...
我希望你能参加我的战斗基地的开幕礼
at a ceremony that will make this battle station operational.
再也没有一个星球敢违抗帝国的统治了
No star system will dare oppose the emperor now.
塔金你越想巩固你的统治
The more you tighten your grip, Tarkin...
就会有越多的反抗
the more star systems will slip through your fingers.
但显示了这个基地的威力之后就不会
Not after we demonstrate the power of this station.
你也帮我决定了
In a way, you have determined...
哪个星球成为他的第一个目标
the choice of the planet that will be destroyed first.
既然你不愿意告诉我们
Since you are reluctant...
叛军的基地所在
to provide us with the location of the rebel base...
我只能选择你的故乡阿尔德兰
I have chosen to test this station's destructive power...
作为我的第一个试验品了
on your home planet of Alderaan.
不！那是个和平的地方
No! Alderaan is peaceful.
我们什么武器也没有，你不可以…
We have no weapons. You can't possibly...
你想要另一个目标吗？军事目标？
You would prefer another target? A military target?
那就说出来啊
Then name the system.
我已经厌倦了，这可是最后一次机会
I grow tired of asking this, so it will be the last time.
叛军基地在哪里？
Where is the rebel base?
塔图因
Dantooine.
他们在塔图因
They're on Dantooine.
你看，维德勋爵
There. You see, Lord Vader?
她也是讲道理的
She can be reasonable.
继续行动，准备好了就发射
Continue with the operation. You may fire when ready.
什么？
What?
你太容易相信人了
You're far too trusting.
塔图因太远了
Dantooine is too remote...
显示不了他的威力，不过别急
to make an effective demonstration, but don't worry.
我们会慢慢跟你的叛军朋友算账的
We will deal with your rebel friends soon enough.
不！
No!
准备发射
Commence primary ignition.
你还好吧？怎么了？
Are you all right? What's wrong?
我感觉气不太稳定
I felt a great disturbance in the Force...
好像无数的声音
as if millions of voices...
在恐惧中尖叫
suddenly cried out in terror...
然后忽然安静下来了
and were suddenly silenced.
我想是有什么不好的事发生了
I fear something terrible has happened.
你继续练习
You'd better get on with your exercises.
现在你不用担心那些臭虫了八
Well, you can forget your troubles with those imperial slugs.
我说了我会甩掉他们的
I told you I'd outrun them.
有人谢我了吗？
Don't everybody thank me at once.
我们不久就会到阿尔德兰了
Anyway, we should be at Alderaan about 0200 hours.
小心了，R2
Now be careful, R2.
啊
Argh!
这是他自找的，乱叫也不会帮你的
He made a fair move. Screaming about it can't help you.
就让让他吧，惹恼一个伍基人是不明智的
Let him have it. It's not wise to upset a Wookiee.
但是没人会怕一个猩猩
But, sir, nobody worries about upsetting a droid.
那是因为猩猩不会把手臂
That's 'cause a droid don't pull people's arms out of their sockets...
从松了的接口里拔出来
when they lose.
伍基人知道怎么做
Wookiees are known to do that.
我明白了
I see your point, sir.
我有个新的建议
I suggest a new strategy, R2.
让伍基人赢
Let the Wookiee win.
记住了，绝地武士能感觉到气从身体里流过
Remember, a Jedi can feel the Force flowing through him.
你是说它控制你的行动？
You mean it controls your actions?
部分的，但他也会服从你的指挥
Partially, but it also obeys your commands.
那些虚伪的宗教和古老的武器
Hokey religions and ancient weapons are no match...
并不怎么适合你
for a good blaster at your side, kid.
你并不相信气，对吗？
You don't believe in the Force, do you?
小子，我什么地方都去过
Kid, I've flown from one side of this galaxy to the other.
也见过不少奇怪的东西
I've seen a lot of strange stuff...
但是我却永远不能相信
but I've never seen anything to make me believe...
有一种力量能控制一切
there's one all-powerful force controlling everything.
没有任何奇怪的力量能够控制我的命运的
There's no mystical energy field controls my destiny.
这只是些小把戏用来唬人的而已
It's all a lot of simple tricks and nonsense.
卢克，我建议你再试一次
I suggest you try it again, Luke.
随心所欲
This time, let go your conscious self...
完全不受约束
and act on instinct.
面罩放下之后我什么都看不见了
With the blast shield down, I can't even see.
那我还怎么战斗阿？
How am I supposed to fight?
你的眼睛会欺骗你的
Your eyes can deceive you.
不能相信他们
Don't trust them.
用你的感觉
Stretch out with your feelings.
瞧，你做的到的
You see? You can do it.
我觉得是幸运
I call it luck.
我觉得从来就没有幸运
In my experience, there's no such thing as luck.
也许对静止的物体有用
Look, good against remotes is one thing.
但对于活动的敌人却又完全不一样了
Good against the living, that's something else.
看来我们到阿尔德兰了
Looks like we're coming up on Alderaan.
我感觉到了一些东西
You know, I did feel something.
我几乎就能看见了
I could almost see the remote.
很好
That's good.
你已经为你的将来
You've taken your first step...
迈出了坚实的一步
into a larger world.
怎么了？
Yes?
我们的侦察船到了塔图因
Our scout ships have reached Dantooine.
他们找到了叛军基地
They found the remains of a rebel base...
但他们估计叛军已经撤离了有一段时间了
but they estimate that it has been deserted for some time.
他们现在正在做地毯式的搜寻
They are now conducting an extensive search of the surrounding systems.
她撒谎！
She lied. She lied to us!
我跟你说了她永远不会
I told you she would never...
背叛那群叛军的
consciously betray the rebellion.
马上处决她
Terminate her immediately.
楚伊，准备好了
Stand by, Chewie. Here we go.
把引擎关掉
Cut in the sublight engines.
妈的…
What the...
我们从外太空进入了流星雨区域
We've come out of hyperspace into a meteor shower.
应该是行星撞击产生的吧
Some kind of asteroid collision.
但是图表上却没有显示
It's not on any of the charts.
怎么了？
What's going on?
我们的位置正确无误，但是却没有阿尔德兰
Our position's correct, except no Alderaan.
什么意思？那它去哪儿了？
What do you mean? Where is it?
我也想问这个问题
That's what I'm trying to tell you, kid.
他不在了，被完整的消灭了
It ain't there. It's been totally blown away.
什么？怎么做到的？
What? How?
被帝国毁灭了
Destroyed by the Empire.
就算是整个帝国舰队也不能消灭整颗行星阿
The entire starfleet couldn't destroy the whole planet.
他会需要一千艘战舰的火力…
It would take 1,000 ships with more firepower than...
又有一艘飞船过来了
There's another ship coming in.
也许他们知道发生了什么
Maybe they know what happened.
这是帝国的战船
It's an imperial fighter.
他盯上我们了！
It followed us!
不，这是艘短程战船
No. It's a short-range fighter.
这里没有任何基地，它是从哪里来的？
There aren't any bases around here. Where did it come from?
看起来它走的很急
It sure is leaving in a big hurry.
如果他们认出我们的话就会有大麻烦了
If they identify us, we're in big trouble.
看来我有办法
Not if I can help it.
楚伊，扰乱他的通信系统
Chewie, jam its transmissions.
让他走也是个不错的选择
It would be as well to let it go.
他离我们的射程太远了
It's too far out of range.
不会很久的
Not for long.
那样小的战船是不能独自进入这么深的太空的
A fighter that size couldn't get this deep into space on its own.
他应该是从整个战队里走丢了
He must have gotten lost, been part of a convoy or something.
他不会活到
Well, he ain't gonna be around long enough...
透露我们的踪迹了
to tell anybody about us.
看，他正飞向那个小的卫星
Look at him. He's heading for that small moon.
我想我可以在他抵达之前击落他
I think I can get him before he gets there. He's almost in range.
这不是卫星
That's no moon.
是一个空间站
It's a space station.
哪有这么大的空间站阿
It's too big to be a space station.
我有一种不祥的预感
I have a very bad feeling about this.
掉头
Turn the ship around.
没错，快掉头！
Yeah. I think you're right. Full reverse!
楚伊，把备用能源也用上！
Chewie, lock in the auxiliary power.
楚伊，快把备用能源也用上！
Chewie, lock in the auxiliary power!
为什么我们还在前进？
Why are we still moving towards it?!
我们被吸住了
We're caught in a tractor beam. It's pulling us in!
你一定能做什么的！
There's got to be something you can do!
我什么也不能做，小子
There's nothing I can do about it, kid.
已经是全速了，我要关引擎了
I'm at full power. I'm gonna have to shut down.
他们不会那么容易逮到我的
They're not gonna get me without a fight.
你赢不了的…
You can't win...
但还有更好的方法
but there are alternatives to fighting.
327号仓位准备
Clear Bay 327.
我们将打开磁场
We are opening the magnetic field.
到你们的岗位上去！
To your stations!
跟我来
Come with me.
把所有防护网关上
Close all outboard shields.
怎么了？
Yes?
我们抓获了一艘货船
We've captured a freighter...
他正试图进入阿尔德兰的废墟
entering the remains of the Alderaan system.
他的外形
Its markings match those of a ship...
跟逃离的那艘吻合
that blasted its way out of Mos Eisley.
他们应该是准备营救公主的
They must be trying to return the stolen plans to the princess.
看来她对我们还有一些作用
She may yet be of some use to us.
1号，5号，7号，9号撤离岗位
Unlock 1, 5, 7, and 9. Release charge.
316到指挥室报道
316, report to control.
船上一个人也没有
There's no one on board, sir.
根据记录指示，船员在起飞后就遗弃了这艘船
According to the log, the crew abandoned ship right after take-off.
这一定是一个诱饵
It must be a decoy, sir.
逃生舱也不见了
Several of the escape pods have been jettisoned.
找到任何机器人吗？
Did you find any droids?
没有，长官
No, sir.
即使有的话应该也逃生了
If there were any on board, they must also have jettisoned.
派一个搜索队上去
Send a scanning crew aboard.
我要彻彻底底检查这艘船
I want every part of this ship checked.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
我感觉到了…
I sense something...
一种好久没有的感觉
a presence I've not felt since...
叫搜查队来
Get me a scanning crew in here on the double.
我要检查这艘船
I want every part of this ship checked.
里面没人
There's no one here.
还好你有这些小仓位
Boy, it's lucky you had these compartments.
那是走私货物用的
I use them for smuggling.
我从来就没想过我会走私自己
I never thought I'd be smuggling myself in 'em.
这太荒谬了
This is ridiculous.
即使我能起飞
Even if I could take off...
我也过不了那磁场
I'd never get past the tractor beam.
这个由我来解决
Leave that to me.
我就知道你这笨蛋会说这个
Damn fool, I knew that you were gonna say that.
你说跟着笨蛋的人
Who's the more foolish...
是不是更笨呢？
the fool or the fool who follows him?
现在就把船交给你
The ship's all yours.
如果找到什么的话
If the scanners pick up anything...
马上报告
report it immediately.
好的，我们走
All right, let's go.
下面的人！
Hey, down there!
你们可以帮一下忙吗？
Could you give us a hand with this?
TK-421，为什么你们不在岗位上？
TK-421, why aren't you at your post?
TK-421，收到了吗？
TK-421, do you copy?
你先接管，信号不太好
Take over. We've got a bad transmitter.
我看看能做什么
I'll see what I can do.
他的叫声和你的嘈杂声没把他们引来
Between his howling and your blasting everything in sight...
还真是一个奇迹
it's a wonder the whole station doesn't know we're here.
让他们来啊
Bring them on!
我宁愿堂堂正正打一架也不要偷偷摸摸的
I'd prefer a straight fight to all this sneakin' around.
我们已经找到电脑接口了
We've found the computer outlet, sir.
插进去，他应该可以破解整个帝国网络
Plug in. He should be able to interpret the entire imperial network.
他说他找到了
He says he's found the main controls...
能源系统的主控制
to the power beam that's holding the ship here.
他会找出准确的位置
He'll try to make the precise location appear on the monitor.
磁场跟主反应堆
The tractor beam is coupled to the main reactor...
一共有7个联系
in seven locations.
任何一处断连
A power loss at one of the terminals...
都可以让飞船离开
will allow the ship to leave.
我想你们应该帮不上忙
I don't think you boys can help.
我要一个人去
I must go alone.
随便吧
Whatever you say.
我已经仁至义尽了
I've done more than I bargained for on this trip already.
我跟你一起去
I want to go with you.
要有耐心，卢克
Be patient, Luke. Stay and watch over the droids.
东西一定要安全的送到
They must be delivered safely...
否则其他系统也会有跟阿尔德兰一样的命运
or other star systems will suffer the same fate as Alderaan.
你跟我的命运不同
Your destiny lies along a different path from mine.
原力会跟你同在的
The Force will be with you always.
这是你说过的，楚伊
You said it, Chewie.
你从哪里找来这么一个老顽固？
Where did you dig up that old fossil?
本是一个很好的人
Ben is a great man.
没错，好的老是惹来麻烦
Yeah, great at getting us into trouble.
你也没有给出什么好的建议阿
I didn't hear you give any ideas.
任何事都比四处闲逛
Well, anything's better than just hangin' around...
然后等着被他们发现好
waiting for 'em to pick us up.
你以为…
Who do you think...
怎么了？
What is it?
我不是很清楚
I'm afraid I'm not quite sure, sir.
他不停的说我找到她了，她在那里
He says "I've found her" and keeps repeating "She's here."
他找到谁了？
Well, who... who has he found?
莉娅公主
Princess Leia.
公主？她在这儿？
The princess? She's here?!
公主？
Princess?
她在哪里？
Where? Where is she?
什么公主啊？
Princess? What's going on?
第五层，AA-23号囚室
Level 5, Detention Block AA-23.
好像她马上就要被处决了
I'm afraid she's scheduled to be terminated.
不！
Oh, no!
我们得做点什么！
We've got to do something!
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
机器人是她的
The droids belong to her.
她就是信息里的人
She's the one in the message.
我们要帮助她
We got to help her.
不要胡思乱想了
Now look, don't get any funny ideas.
那老头让我们在这里呆着
The old man wants us to wait right here.
但他不知道公主在这里
But he didn't know she was here.
找到去囚室的路
Just find a way back into that detention block.
我什么地方也不会去的
I'm not going anywhere.
他们要处决她了
They're going to execute her.
刚刚你还说
Look, a few minutes ago, you said...
你不想在这里等死
you didn't want to just wait here to be captured.
现在你又想留下来了？
Now all you want to do is stay?
但我从来没想过
Marching into the detention area...
要去囚室
is not what I had in mind.
但他们要杀了她！
But they're gonna kill her!
总比杀了我好
Better her than me.
她很富有
She's rich.
富有？
Rich?
又有钱又有势
Mm-hmm. Rich, powerful.
如果你去救她的话，报酬可是…
Listen, if you were to rescue her, the reward would be...
什么？
What?
超出你的想象
Well, more well than you can imagine.
我的胃口可大了
I don't know. I can imagine quite a bit.
你会得到的
You'll get it.
最好这样
I better.
你会的
You will.
小子，最好你说得没错
All right, kid. You better be right about this.
当然
All right.
你的计划是？
What's your plan?
恩
Um...
你可以把那手铐递给我吗？
3PO, hand me those binders there, will you?
好的
O.K.
我现在要把它戴在你身上
Now... I'm gonna put these on you.
汉，你来吧
O.K. Han, you... you put those on.
别担心，楚伊
Don't worry, Chewie.
我想我知道他想做什么
I think I know what he has in mind.
卢克主人，请允许我问一下
Master Luke, sir, pardon me for asking...
我跟R2被发现的话该怎么办？
but what should R2 and I do if we're discovered here?
关上门
Lock the door.
希望他们没有炸药吧
And hope they don't have blasters.
这听起来并不怎么可靠
That isn't very reassuring.
517去检查控制室
517 to scanner control.
316向控制室报道
316, report to control.
53到上层闸门
53 to upper bay door.
在这个头盔下我什么也看不见
I can't see a thing in this helmet.
这不会管用的
This is not gonna work.
你前面为什么不讲？
Why didn't you say so before?
我说了阿
I did say so before.
你们要把这东西带去哪里？
Where are you taking this... thing?
转去1138号囚室
Prisoner transfer from Cell Block 1138.
我没有被通知
I wasn't notified.
让我确认一下
I'll have to clear it.
小心，他的手铐松了！
Look out! He's loose!
他会把我们都撕成碎片的！
He'll tear us all apart!
我来！
I'll get him!
小心！
Look out!
我们得找到是哪间囚室先
We gotta find out which cell this princess of yours is in.
是这间-2187
Here it is... 2187.
你去找她，我来缠住他们
You go and get her. I'll hold them here.
一切都控制住了
Uh... Uh, everything's under control.
情况正常
Situation normal.
怎么了？
What happened?
武器有点失常
Had a slight weapons malfunction...
现在都已经没问题了
but, uh, everything's perfectly all right now.
我们很好，谢谢
We're fine... We're all fine here now. Thank you.
你怎么了？
How are you?
我们正派一个小队过去
We're sending a squad up.
有情况，有情况！
Uh, negative, negative!
我们这里的反应堆泄漏
We have a... a reactor leak here, uh, now.
我们需要几分钟来解决
Give us a few minutes to lock it down.
大规模泄漏，很严重
Uh, large leak, very dangerous.
你是谁？你的号码是多少？
Who is this? What's your operating number?
恩
Uh...
没什么意义的对话
Boring conversation anyway.
卢克，有人要来了！
Luke! We're gonna have company!
你会不会太矮了？
Aren't you a little short for a stormtrooper?
啊？
Huh?
你的制服
Oh, the uniform.
我叫天行者卢克，我是来救你的
I'm Luke Skywalker. I'm here to rescue you.
你是谁？
You're who?
我是来救你的，我有你的R2
I'm here to rescue you. I've got your R2 unit.
我跟本 科努比一起来的
I'm here with Ben Kenobi.
本 科努比？他在哪里？
Ben Kenobi?! Where is he?
快！
Come on!
他在这儿
He is here.
欧比 旺 科努比？
Obi-Wan Kenobi?
你为什么会这样觉得？
What makes you think so?
我的气在振动
A tremor in the Force.
上次我感觉到他
The last time I felt it...
是在我的老师身边
was in the presence of my old master.
但他应该已经死了阿
Surely he must be dead by now.
永远不要轻视气
Don't underestimate the Force.
绝地武士已经灭绝了
The Jedi are extinct.
他们已经在这个宇宙消失
Their fire has gone out of the universe.
你是他们之中唯一的幸存者了
You, my friend, are all that's left of their religion.
怎么了
Yes.
我们有一个警报
We have an emergency alert...
在AA-23囚室
in Detention Block AA-23.
公主？
The princess?
全面警戒
Put all sections on alert.
欧比 旺来了
Obi-Wan is here.
我感觉到他的气了
The Force is with him.
如果你的判断没错的话
If you're right...
他就不容许逃走
he must not be allowed to escape.
这不是他的计划
Escape is not his plan.
我要单独面对他
I must face him alone.
到我后面！
Get behind me! Get behind me!
看你的左边
Watch your left.
他们去了闸门
They went down the cell bay.
这里行不通
Can't get out that way.
你把我们唯一的去路给堵住了
Looks like you managed to cut off our only escape route.
看来你是想回到你的囚室了，殿下
Maybe you'd like it back in your cell, Your Highness.
C-3PO, C-3PO!
怎么了？
Yes, sir?
有什么路能走出去吗？
Are there any other ways out of the cell bay?
我们被堵住了
We've been cut off!
什么？我听不到
What was that? I didn't copy.
我说已经全面警戒了
I said all systems have been alerted to your presence, sir.
只有主通道是开的
The main entrance seems to be the only way in or out.
你那一层的信息被限制了
All other information on your level is restricted.
把门打开！
Open up in there!
打开门！
不！
Oh, no!
已经没有路了
There isn't any other way out!
我不能永远挡着他们，现在怎么办？
I can't hold them off forever! Now what?!
好一个营救！
This is some rescue!
你们进来却没有一个计划出去？
You came in here, and you didn't have a plan for getting out?
亲爱的，他才是策划者！
He's the brains, sweetheart!
我没有…
Well, I didn't...
你在干什么？
What the hell are you doing?
总的有个办法啊
Somebody has to save our skins.
进垃圾道，快！
Into the garbage chute, fly boy.
快进！
- Get in there! - Arrgh!
快进去你这大家伙！
Get in there, you big furry oaf!
我才不管那味道呢
I don't care what you smell.
快进去，什么也别想
Get in there, and don't worry about it.
好女孩！
Wonderful girl!
要不我就杀了她
Either I'm going to kill her...
要不我会开始喜欢她
or I'm beginning to like her.
快进去！
Get in there!
啊！
Ah!
这么个好主意
The garbage chute was a really wonderful idea.
这是什么味道啊！
What an incredible smell you've discovered!
快出去
Let's get out of here.
走开
Get away from there.
等一下！
No, wait!
你忘了吗？我已经试过了！
Will you forget it?! I already tried it!
这里被磁场封住了
It's magnetically sealed.
把那东西拿开！你会杀了我们的！
Put that thing away! You're gonna get us all killed!
没错，我的神！
Absolutely, Your Worship.
一切都很好直至你把我们带进来！
Look, I had everything under control till you led us down here!
他们不会需要多久
Ya know, it's not gonna take 'em long...
来知道我们去哪儿的！
to figure out what happened to us!
没什么比这个更糟的了
It could be worse.
没错
It's worse.
这里有生物
There's something alive in here.
那是你的幻觉
That's your imagination.
有东西从我的腿边经过
Something just moved past my leg.
你看见了吗？
Look! Did you see that?
什么？
What?
小子！
Kid!
卢克！
Luke!
卢克，抓住这个！
Luke! Luke, grab hold of this!
妈的，我的枪被卡住了
Blast it! My gun's jammed.
哪儿？
Where?
随便！
Anywhere!
卢克！
Luke, Luke!
快帮他！
Help him!
怎么了？
What happened?
我不知道
I don't know.
他们忽然松开我走了
It just let go of me and disappeared.
我有不祥的预感
I got a bad feeling about this.
墙在动！
The walls are moving!
别站着不动！
Don't just stand there!
用什么东西顶住
Try and brace it with something.
快帮我！
Help me!
等一下
Wait a minute!
3PO！
3PO!
快点3PO！
Come in, 3PO!
3PO！
3PO!
它去哪儿了？
Where could he be?
到位，快找
Take over. See to him.
在这儿
Look, there.
他们疯了
They're madmen.
他们去监狱那一层了
They're heading for the prison level.
如果够快的话也许还能抓到他们
If you hurry, you might catch them.
跟我走
Follow me.
你在这里守着
You stand guard.
快
Come on.
哦！
Oh!
我的朋友出了一点故障
All this excitement has overrun the circuits in my counterpart here.
如果你不介意我想带他去维修
If you don't mind, I'd like to take him down to maintenance.
好
All right.
3PO！
3PO!
快，3PO！
Come in, 3PO!
3PO！
3PO!
到上面去！
Get on top!
我上不去
I can't.
他跑去哪里？3PO
Where could he be?! 3PO!
3PO，你答话！
3PO, will you come in!
他们不在这里
They aren't here.
一定出事了
Something must have happened to them.
看他们是否被抓了
See if they've been captured.
快点！
Hurry.
有件事可确定
One thing's for sure...
我们都要变瘦了
we're all gonna be a lot thinner.
到上面去
Get on top of it.
我在努力了
I'm trying.
谢天谢地！ 帝国军还没找到他们
Thank goodness they haven't found them.
他们去哪里了呢？
Where could they be?
用通话器？
"Use the comlink"?
我忘了我把它关了
Oh, my. I forgot. I turned it off.
你在吗？先生？
Are you there, sir?
3PO！
3PO!
我们发生了点问题…
We've had some problems.
你闭嘴听我说好吗？
Will you shut up and listen to me?!
关闭囚犯区的垃圾库电力 好吗？！
Shut down all the garbage mashers on the detention level, will ya?!
你听到了吗？
Do you copy!?
把囚犯区的垃圾库电力都关闭！
Shut down all the garbage mashers on the detention level!
没错！ 全部关闭，快呀！
No! Shut them all down. Hurry!
什么？
What?
哈哈！
Ha ha!
你听他们的叫声，他们就要死了，R2！
Listen to them. They're dying, R2!
天咒我吧！
Curse my metal body!
我的动作不够快 全是我的错，我可怜的主人
I wasn't fast enough. It's all my fault! My poor master.
我们没事了！ 太棒了，你做的太好了
We're all right! You did great!
打开这里的压力门
Hey! Open the pressure maintenance hatch...
我们在哪里？
on unit number... Where are we?
我们在 32-63-827 下面
3263827!
只要避免再有女性建议，
If we can just avoid any more female advice...
我们就能离开这儿
we ought to be able to get outta here.
我们快走吧！
Well, let's get moving.
你去那儿？
Where are you going?
等等！ 他们会听到
No, wait! They'll hear!
过来！ 你这懦夫
Come here, you big coward.
楚伊，过来
Chewie, come here.
听着！
Listen...
我不知你是谁？从何而来
I don't know who you are or where you came from...
从现在开始，照我的话作，好吗？
but from now on, you do as I tell you, OK?
听着！殿下…
Look, Your Worshipfulness...
我们先弄清楚
let's get one thing straight.
我只听命于一个人，我！
I take orders from just one person... me.
你还活着真是奇迹
It's a wonder you're still alive.
谁来搬开这活动地板？
Will somebody get this big walking carpet out of my way?
没有奖赏值得我经受这一切
No reward is worth this.
请把我例行的报告给我
Give me regular reports, please.
好的
Right.
你知道是怎么回事吗？
Do you know what's going on?
也许又是一次演习吧
Maybe it's another drill.
看到那个新的 VT-16了吗？
You seen that new VT-16?
听别人说了
Yeah. Some of the other guys were telling me about it.
他们说它值得一看
They say it's... it's quite a thing to see...
那是什么？
What was that?
没什么正在排气
Ah, it's nothing. Outgassing.
不要担心
Don't worry about it.
船就在那边了
There she is.
C3PO！ 你听到吗？
C-3PO? Do you copy?
是的！
Yes, sir.
- 你安全吗？ - 目前是
- Are you safe? - For the moment.
我们在主机棚，飞船那边
We're in the main hangar across from the ship.
我们就在你上面！ 待命
We're right above you. Stand by.
你的船？
You came in that thing?
你比我想的还勇敢
You're braver than I thought.
很好！ 走吧
Nice! Come on.
是他们！
It's them!
开火！
Blast them!
回船去
Get back to the ship!
你去哪里？回来！
Where are you going? Come back!
他的确有勇气！
He certainly has courage.
如果他这样丢掉自己的性命…
What good will it do us...
对我们会有什么好处呢？来
if he gets himself killed? Come on.
我们转弯转错了
I think we took a wrong turn.
没有锁
There's no lock.
这应让能挡住他们一阵
That oughta hold them for a while.
快！ 我们得过去
Quick! We've got to get across.
找出控制器把桥延伸出去
Find the controls that extend the bridge.
我刚把它打坏
I think I just blasted it.
但他们就要过来了呀！
They're coming through!
拿着！
Here, hold this.
他们来了
Here they come.
好运
For luck.
他们可能单独行动
We think they may be splitting up.
已经到了5楼或6楼
They may be on Level 5 and 6 now, sir.
他们人呢？
Where could they be?
把门关上！
Close the blast doors!
把门打开！ 把门打开！
Open the blast doors! Open the blast doors!
我在等你！欧比旺！
I've been waiting for you, Obi-Wan.
我们终于再度见面
We meet again at last.
循环完成
The circle is now complete.
我离开你时是学生
When I left you, I was but the learner.
如今我是大师了
Now I am the master.
邪恶大师，达斯・维德
Only a master of evil, Darth.
你的力量太弱了，老头子
Your powers are weak, old man.
你赢不了的，达斯・维德
You can't win, Darth.
如果你将我击倒…
If you strike me down...
我会比你所想像的还要有力
I shall become more powerful than you can possibly imagine.
你不该回来
You should not have come back.
我们快离开这里？
Didn't we just leave this party?
你们被什么耽误了？
What kept you?
我们遇到些老朋友
We, uh, ran into some old friends.
船没事吧？
The ship all right?
看上去很好，只要我们能上得去
It seems OK, if we can get to it.
希望老头消除了磁力牵引光束
I just hope the old man got the tractor beam out of commission.
看！
Look!
走吧！ R2，我们要走了
Come on, R2, we're going.
这是我们的机会，快走！
Now's our chance! Go!
本？
Ben?
不！
No!
快来呀！
Come on!
卢克，已经太迟了！
Luke, it's too late!
把开关打坏！
Blast the door, kid!
快跑！卢克！
Run, Luke, run!
希望老头破坏了磁力牵引光束…
I hope that old man got that tractor beam out of commission...
我们就能迅速离去 好！ 发动！
or this is gonna be a real short trip. O.K. Hit it!
如果有他们的哨兵飞船
We're coming up on their sentry ships.
挡住它们
Hold them off.
升起防护网，将主要炮管装满
Angle the deflector shields while I charge up the main guns.
我无法相信他已死了
I can't believe he's gone.
你也无能为力
There wasn't anything you could have done.
来吧！ 这件事还未完呢
Come on, buddy. We're not out of this yet.
你进来了吗？好！ 保持警觉
You in, kid? OK, stay sharp.
他们来了！
Here they come.
他们来得太快！
They're coming in too fast!
我们的侧面失去控制！
We've lost the lateral controls!
不要担心！ 这船能够撑住
Don't worry. She'll hold together.
宝贝，稳住！
Hear me, baby? Hold together.
我打中它了！ 太好了
Got him! I got him!
不要就此自满
Great, kid! Don't get cocky.
外面还有２个！
There's still two more of them out there!
这就对了！ 我们成功了！
That's it! We did it!
我们成功了！
We did it!
救命！ 我觉得我好像在融化！这都是你的错！
Help! I think I'm melting! This is all your fault!
他们走远了吗？
Are they away?
他们刚冲进超太空
They've just made the jump into hyperspace.
你确信追踪器装好了？
You're sure the homing beacon is secure aboard their ship?
我这可是冒很大的险
I'm taking an awful risk, Vader.
这招最好有效
This had better work.
还算成功的援救，是吧？
Not a bad bit of rescuing, huh?
有时连我自己也感惊奇
You know, sometimes I amaze even myself.
这并不难呀
That doesn't sound too hard.
他们是故意让我们走
They let us go.
这是我们能轻易逃离的唯一解释
It's the only explanation for the ease of our escape.
轻易，你说这样是轻易？
Easy? You call that easy?
他们追踪我们
They're tracking us.
不可能对这条船的
Not this ship, sister.
起码R2身上的情报未被破坏
At least the information in R2 is still intact.
什么情报如此重要？它带着什么？
What's so important? What's he carrying?
那个战斗站的结构图
The technical readouts of that battle station.
我只希望等我们分析时…
I only hope that when the data's analyzed...
能找出它的弱点
a weakness can be found.
这件事还未结束呢
It's not over yet.
对我可是结束了
It is for me, sister.
我参与此事不是为了你的革命…
Look, I ain't in this for your revolution...
也不是为了你
and I'm not in it for you, Princess.
我是期望有优厚的报酬
I expect to be well paid.
我是为钱参与此事
I'm in it for the money.
你不用担心你的报酬
You needn't worry about your reward.
如果你就只爱钱…
If money is all that you love...
那就是你会获得的
then that's what you'll receive.
你的朋友，好个佣兵
Your friend is quite a mercenary.
我看他不关心任何事…
I wonder if he really cares about anything...
或任何人
or anybody.
我关心呀！
I care.
所以…
So...
你觉得她如何？
what do you think of her, Han?
我尽量不去想她，孩子
I'm trying not to, kid.
很好
Good.
不过我认为她很有胆识
Still, she's got a lot of spirit.
我不知道你说呢？
I don't know. What do you think?
公主配我这样的人，你觉得如何…
You think a princess and a guy like me...
不好！
No!
你获救了
You're safe.
当我们听到奥的朗的消息时…
When we heard about Alderaan...
我们最害怕
we feared the worst.
我们没时间伤心了，指挥官
We have no time for sorrows, Commander.
你必须使用R2身上的情况…
You must use the information in this R2 unit...
来策划攻击行动
to help plan the attack.
那是我们唯一的希望
It's our only hope.
是的
Yes.
我们正接近耶比星球
We're approaching the planet Yavin.
叛军基地在另一头的卫星上
The rebel base is on a moon on the far side.
我们打算绕耶比星飞行
We are preparing to orbit the planet.
帝国战斗站严密的防卫…
The battle station is heavily shielded...
具有的火力…
and carries a firepower...
比半个星际舰队还要强
greater than half the starfleet.
它的防卫措施是根据大型直接的攻击而设计
Its defenses are designed around a direct large-scale assault.
单人战斗机应能穿越外层的防卫
A small, one-man fighter should be able to penetrate the outer defense.
请问，首长…
Pardon me for asking, sir...
我们小型战斗机对抗它又有何用？
but what good are snub fighters going to be against that?
帝国认为小型单人机…
The Empire doesn't consider a small, one-man fighter...
不具威胁…
to be any threat...
不然他们会有更严密的防卫系统
or they'd have a tighter defense.
莉娅公主所提供的敌军分析图…
An analysis of the plans provided by Princess Leia...
显示他们的基地有个弱点
has demonstrated a weakness in the battle station.
要接近并不容易
The approach will not be easy.
你们必须低飞到这个狭沟…
You're required to maneuver straight down this trench...
然后沿着狭沟而行，直到这一点
and skim the surface to this point.
攻击目标区仅两米宽
The target area is only 2 meters wide.
是个反应炉排气口…
It's a small thermal exhaust port...
就在主排气口的下方
right below the main port.
孔道直通反应炉系统
The shaft leads directly to the reactor system.
正中目标能引起连锁反应…
A precise hit will start a chain reaction...
毁灭帝国军战斗站
which should destroy the station.
只有正中目标才能引起连锁反应
Only a precise hit will set up a chain reaction.
此排气口有防击保护层…
The shaft is ray-shielded...
所以你们必须使用质子弹
so you'll have to use proton torpedoes.
这连电脑也办不到
That's impossible, even for a computer.
并非不可能的 我以前在家乡常用 T16，击中我的面包中心点
It's not impossible. I used to bull's-eye womp rats in my T-16 back home.
那还没有两米宽
They're not much bigger than 2 meters.
上你们的宇宙飞船吧！ 愿原力与你们同在！
Then man your ships, and may the Force be with you.
全速环绕耶比星球
Orbiting the planet at maximum velocity.
叛军基地所在的卫星…
The moon with the rebel base...
将在30分钟内进入射程
will be in range in 30 minutes.
这将是一个值得纪念的日子
This will be a day long remembered.
我们己经见到欧比旺的末日…
It has seen the end of Kenobi...
很快也要见到叛军的末日
and will soon see the end of the rebellion.
全体飞行队员就位
All flight crews, man your stations.
你领到你的赏金，你就要走了？
So... you got your reward and you're just leaving, then?
是的
That's right. Yeah.
我还有债要还
I got some old debts I got to pay off with this stuff.
就算没有债要还…
And even if I didn't...
你想我会傻到留下来？
you don't think I'd be fool enough to stick around here, do ya?
为何不跟我们走？
Why don't you come with us?
你能打仗，我用得上你
You're pretty good in a fight. We could use ya.
好了！ 你何不看看四周？
Come on. Why don't you take a look around?
你知道即将发生什么事？
You know what's about to happen...
知道他们要对抗谁？
what they're up against.
他们用得上你这样的好飞行员
They could use a good pilot like you.
你这样是背弃他们
You're turning your back on them.
人死了，赏金有什么用？
What good's a reward if you ain't around to use it?
况且攻击帝国军战斗站…
Besides, attacking that battle station...
并非我认为的勇气之举
ain't my idea of courage.
我看更像…自杀
It's more like... suicide.
好吧！
All right.
保重你自己
Take care of yourself, Han.
我想那是你最拿手的事，对吧？
I guess that's what you're best at, isn't it?
卢克
Hey, Luke.
愿原力与你同在
May the Force be with you.
你看个什么劲儿？
What are you looking at?
我知道我在作什么
I know what I'm doing.
所有飞行员就位
All pilots to your stations.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
是汉！
Oh, it's Han.
我不知道，我以为他改变主意了
I don't know. I really thought he'd change his mind.
他必须走他自己的路
He's got to follow his own path.
别人没办法替他选择
No one can choose it for him.
我真希望本也在这儿
I only wish Ben were here.
打开飞行管道
Open main launch tubes.
Main launch tubes opening, sir.
嘿，卢克！
Hey, Luke!
毕格斯！
Biggs!
你好吗？
I don't believe it. How are you?
很好
Great.
上去吗？
Hey, coming up?
我马上去与你会合…
I'll be right up there with you...
有很多话要告诉你
and have I got stories to tell you.
你有把握能应付这种机型吗？
Are you sure you can handle this ship?
首长，卢克是外太空中最厉害的飞行员
Sir, Luke is the best bush pilot in the outer-rim territories.
你应该能胜任
You'll do all right.
谢谢，我会尽力的
Thank you, sir. I'll try.
该上机了
I gotta get aboard.
回程再听你的故事好了，好吗？
We'll hear all your stories when we get back, all right?
好的
All right.
毕格斯
Hey, Biggs.
告诉过你我会成功的
I told you I'd make it someday.
就像往常一样，卢克
It'll be like old times, Luke.
没人挡的住我们
They'll never stop us.
你的R2好像很旧了
Hey, this R2 unit of yours seems a bit beat up.
要换个新吗？
You want a new one?
才不呢！
Not on your life.
我和这个小机器人合作很久
That little droid and I have been through a lot together.
你还好吗？R2
You OK, R2?
好！
Good.
金色编队 准备起飞
Gold squadron, begin take-off procedure.
稳住！ R2，你必须回来
Hang on tight, R2. You've got to come back.
你不想让我的生活无聊吧
You wouldn't want my life to get boring, would you?
卢克，原力将与你同在！
Luke, the Force will be with you.
提高警觉
Standby alert.
死亡星球接近
Death Star approaching.
预计15分钟内到达射程
Estimated time to firing range, 15 minutes.
所有飞行员向我报告
All wings report in.
红色 10 号待命！
Red 10 standing by.
红色 7 号待命！
Red Seven standing by.
红色 3 号待命！
Red Three standing by.
红色 6 号待命！
Red Six standing by.
红色 9 号待命！
Red Nine standing by.
红色 2 号待命！
Red Two standing by.
红色 11 号待命！
Red 11 standing by.
红色 5 号待命！
Red Five standing by.
进入攻击队形
Lock S-foils in attack position.
我们正通过磁场
We're passing through the magnetic field.
跟紧！
Hold tight.
设定防护装置，双层前护网
Switch your deflectors on. Double front.
这东西如此庞大！
Look at the size of that thing!
关闭快门！ 红色２号 加速至攻击速度
Cut the chatter, Red Two. Accelerate to attack speed.
这就是了，小伙子们！
This is it, boys.
红色队长！ 这里是金色队长
Red Leader, this is Gold Leader.
正听着，金色队长
I copy, Gold Leader.
我要朝目标口前进
We're starting for the target shaft now.
我们已经就位
We're in position.
我要冲进去…
I'm going to cut across the axis...
吸引他们的火力
and try and draw their fire.
强火力，在 23 度
Heavy fire, boss, 23 degrees.
看到了，保持低飞
I see it. Stay low.
我是红色 5 号，我要进去了
This is Red Five. I'm going in.
卢克，拉起来！
Luke, pull up!
你还好吗？
Are you all right?
机身擦到一点但没事
I got a little cooked, but I'm O.K.
有 30 架叛军的战斗机，维达勋爵…
We count 30 rebel ships, Lord Vader...
但他们好小…
but they're so small...
穿越我们的镭射光
they're evading our turbolasers.
我们得一架一架毁掉他们
We'll have to destroy them ship to ship.
让飞行员上战斗机
Get the crews to their fighters.
全体注意！
Watch yourself. There's a lot of fire coming...
右边的炮塔，攻击猛烈！
from the right side of that deflection tower.
我来
I'm on it.
掩护我，福金
I'm going in. Cover me, Porkins.
我跟着你，红色3号
I'm right with you, Red Three.
我有个问题
I've got a problem here.
退出！
Eject.
我没事
I can hold it.
拉起来！
Pull up!
不！
No, I'm all...
叛军基地…
The rebel base will be in firing range...
在 7 分钟内进入射程
in seven minutes.
卢克，信任你的感觉
Luke, trust your feelings.
飞行领队，我们收到新的信号
Squad leaders, we've picked up a new group of signals.
敌军战斗机朝你的方向飞去
Enemy fighters coming your way.
我的扫描器上没有显示，我什么也没看到
My scope's negative. I don't see anything.
用你的目视扫描
Pick up your visual scanning.
他们来了！
Here they come.
小心了！ 有一个在你尾巴后面
Watch it. You've got one on your tail.
击中了！
I'm hit!
已击中一架，小心！
You've picked one up! Watch it!
我看不到
I can't see it!
跟得很紧，无法甩掉它！
He's on me tight. I can't shake him!
我马上就来了
I'll be right there.
有几个战斗机脱离主队…
Several fighters have broken off...
来掩护我
from the main group. Come with me.
集合！集合！
Fall in! Fall in!
小心你的后面，卢克
Watch your back, Luke.
小心你的后面
Watch your back.
敌机逼近
Fighters above you, coming in.
我被击中，但还好
I'm hit, but not bad.
R2，看你能不能想办法
R2, see what you can do with it.
等着
Hang on back there.
红色6号，你看到红色5号吗？
Red Six, can you see Red Five?
炮火还是很猛
There's a heavy fire zone.
红色5号，你在哪里？
Red Five, where are you?
我摆脱不了他！
I can't shake him!
稳住！卢克
I'm on him, Luke. Hold on.
毕格斯！你在哪里？
Blast it, Biggs! Where are you?
谢了，威治
Thanks, Wedge.
打的好！
Good shooting, Wedge. Red Leader...
这里是金色队长
this is Gold Leader.
我们要开始我们的行动
We're starting our attack run.
知道了，队长，马上就位
I copy, Gold Leader. Move into position.
攻击队形
Stay in attack formation.
锁定排气孔
The exhaust port is marked and locked in.
把动力转至…
Switch all power...
把所有动力转到前面防弹
to front deflector screen.
把动力转至…
Switch all power...
把所有动力转到前面防弹
to front deflector screen.
你看有多少火炮，金色 5 号？
How many guns do you think, Gold Five?
大约 20 门
Say about 20 guns...
有些在表面，有些在塔上
some on the surface, some on the towers.
死亡星球 5 分钟内进入射程
Death Star will be in range in five minutes.
启动瞄准电脑
Switch to targeting computer.
电脑收到讯号
Computer locked. Getting a signal.
大炮…停止发射了
The guns! They've stopped!
稳住你们的尾部变流器
Stabilize your rear deflectors.
小心敌军战斗机
Watch for enemy fighters.
他们来了！有 3 架在 2 点 10 分位置
They're coming in! Three marks at 210.
在我的侧位，掩护我
I'll take them myself. Cover me.
是的
Yes, sir.
我没办法行动
It's no good. I can't maneuver.
紧跟目标
Stay on target.
我们太近了
We're too close.
紧跟目标
Stay on target.
离远一点！
Loosen up!
金色呼叫红色队长，失去两架战机
Gold Five to Red Leader, lost Tiree, lost Hutch.
知道了，金色队长
I copy, Gold Leader.
从后面来的
They came from behind.
已分析他们的攻击
We've analyzed their attack, sir...
有危险
and there is a danger.
要我准备好你的宇宙飞船吗？
Should I have your ship standing by?
在我们胜利的时刻撤退？
Evacuate in our moment of triumph?
我看你高估他们的机会了
I think you overestimate their chances.
叛军基地 3 分钟，接近中
Rebel base, three minutes and closing.
红色战斗机　这里是红色队长
Red boys, this is Red Leader.
61 位置会合
Rendezvous at mark 6.1.
这里是红色 2 号，向你飞来
This is Red Two flying toward you.
红色 3 号待命
Red Three standing by.
红色队长，这里是一号基地
Red Leader, this is Base One.
保留一半人马…
Keep half your group out of range...
准备展开下一波行动
for the next run.
知道了，一号基地卢克，红色 2 号及 3 号
Copy, Base One. Luke, take Red Two and Three.
在这儿等我的讯号展开你们的行动
Hold up here and wait for my signal to start your run.
这就是了！
This is it!
我们现在应该已经看到
We should be able to see it by now.
注意那些战斗机
Keep your eyes open for those fighters.
太多干扰
There's too much interference.
红色 5 号，你能看到敌军战斗机吗？
Red Five, can you see them from where you are?
什么也没看… 慢着！3点5分方向
No sign of any... Wait. Coming in.35.
我看到了
I see them.
进入射程
I'm in range.
目标快要到了
Target's coming up.
只要挡住他们几秒钟
Just hold them off for a few seconds.
排成对形
Close up formation.
快到了
Almost there.
我摆脱不掉他们，他们就在我后面
You'd better let her loose. They're right behind me.
就快到了
Almost there.
我挡不住他们
I can't hold them.
发射了！
It's away!
击中了吗？
It's a hit!
没中！ 没中！ 没进去
Negative, negative. It didn't go in.
只在表面爆炸
It just impacted on the surface.
红色队长，我们就在你上面
Red Leader, we're right above you.
转向05 方向，我会掩护你
Turn to.05. We'll cover for you.
我刚损失右舷引擎
Stay there. I just lost my starboard engine.
展开你的攻击行动
Get set up for your attack run.
叛军基地，一分钟，继续接近
Rebel base, one minute and closing.
毕格斯，威治，我们向目标接近
Biggs, Wedge, let's close it up.
我们要全力冲进去
We're going in full throttle.
你替我挡住那些战斗机
That ought to keep those fighters off our back.
紧跟着你
Right with you, boss.
你的速度能及时击中吗？
Luke, at that speed, will you be able to pull out in time?
没问题，顺顺利利地
It'll be just like Beggars Canyon back home.
我们在你后面，掩护你
We'll stay back far enough to cover you.
我看得到塔…
My scope shows the tower...
但看不到排气口
but I can't see the exhaust port.
你确信电脑能击中吗？
Are you sure the computer can hit it?
你自己要小心，要加速前速
Watch yourself. Increase speed, full throttle.
炮塔呢？
What about that tower?
你管敌机！
You worry about those fighters!
我来管炮塔！
I'll worry about the tower!
R2，稳定器又松了
R2, that stabilizer's broken loose again.
你把它固定好吗？
See if you can't lock it down.
敌机来了，３点方向
Fighters coming in.3.
我被击中，我不能跟你了
I'm hit! I can't stay with you!
退开，威治 你在后面也帮不了忙
Get clear, Wedge. You can't do any more good back there.
抱歉！
Sorry.
让他走！ 跟着领队战斗机
Let him go. Stay on the leader.
快点！ 卢克，这次他们速度更快
Hurry, Luke. They're coming in much faster this time.
我们挡不住他们
We can't hold them.
R2，加速！
R2, try and increase the power.
快点！ 卢克！
Hurry up, Luke!
快点！快点！
Quick! Quick!
叛军基地，30 秒，继续接近
Rebel base, 30 seconds and closing.
我来对付领队
I'm on the leader.
支持下去！ R2
Hang on, R2.
使用宇宙之原力，卢克
Use the Force, Luke.
放手去作！
Let go, Luke.
这架原力很强烈
The Force is strong with this one.
卢克！ 相信我
Luke, trust me.
他的电脑关掉了
His computer's off.
卢克！ 你关掉瞄准的电脑！
Luke, you switched off your targeting computer!
怎么回事？
What's wrong?
没事！ 我很好
Nothing. I'm all right.
我损失了R2！
I've lost R2!
星球受到威胁
The Death Star has cleared the planet.
叛军基地在射程内
Rebel base in range.
准备好了就射击
You may fire when ready.
开始第一次点火！
Commence primary ignition.
我逮到你了！
I have you now.
什么？
What?
喔！！
Yahoo!
小心！
Look out!
没障碍了，小子 现在快炸掉目标，我们回家
You're all clear, kid! Now let's blow this thing and go home!
预备！
Stand by.
射得好，小子！
Great shot, kid!
百里挑一
That was one in a million!
记着！ 原力将与你同在…永远
Remember, the Force will be with you always.
卢克！
Luke!
嘿！嘿！
Hey! Hey!
我就知道你会回来！ 我就知道
I knew you'd come back. I just knew it.
我才不让你独享功劳…
Well, I wasn't going to let you get all the credit...
拿走所有赏金
and take all the reward.
我就知道你不是只看重钱
Hey, I knew there was more to you than money.
糟了！
Oh, no!
R2，你能听到我说话吗？说话呀！
Oh, my. R2, can you hear me?
说点什么 你能修理他吧
Say something. You can repair him, can't you?
我们马上着手
We'll get to work on him right away.
你们一定把他修好
You must repair him.
如果我有什么电路能帮助…
Sir, if any of my circuits or gears will help...
我很乐意提供
I'll gladly donate them.
他会修复的
He'll be all right.